嗯，也许我们应该开始吧，因为我们已经有很长时间了
um maybe maybe we should get started um
it's been a long time since we've all
晚上在同一地方，希望大家今天过得不错，我想
been in the same place at night I hope
everybody's doing well today I'd like to
谈论扳手谈论这篇文章的原因是它很少见
talk about spanner the reason to talk
about this paper is that it's a rare
系统示例提供了基于广泛数据的分布式事务
example of a system provides distributed
transactions over data that's widely
分离的数据可能分散在整个互联网上，
separated that is data that might be
scattered all over the internet and
我在Saul的生产系统中从来没有做过的不同数据中心
different data centers I'm Saul most
never done in production systems of
当然，非常需要能够进行交易
course it's extremely desirable to be
able to have transactions the
程序员非常喜欢它，并且非常希望能够传播数据
programmers really like it and also
extremely desirable to have data spread
在整个网络上进行容错处理并确保数据
all over the network for both for fault
tolerance and to ensure that data is
几乎每个想要使用它的人附近都有一个数据副本，并且
near that there's a copy of the data
near everybody who wants to use it and
在实现此扳手的过程中，至少使用了两个巧妙的想法，一个是
on the way to achieving this spanner
used at least two neat ideas one is that
他们运行两阶段提交，但实际上是在复制的paxos上运行它
they run two-phase commit but they
actually run it over paxos replicated
参与者我是为了避免问题的两阶段提交
participants I'm in order to avoid the
problem the two-phase commit that a
崩溃的协调员可以阻止所有人，另一个有趣的想法是
crashed coordinator can block everyone
and the other interesting idea is that
他们使用同步时间来获得非常有效的只读
they use synchronize time in order to
have very efficient read-only
交易和系统是实际上非常成功的
transactions and the system is is that
actually been very successful it's used
Google内的许多不同服务带来了很多麻烦
a lot by many many different services
inside of Google it's been turned by
Google成为一种产品，可为其基于云的客户提供服务，
Google into a product to service for
their cloud-based customers and it's
启发了许多其他研究和其他系统
inspired a bunch of other research and
other systems both sort of by the
例如，这种广域交易是可能的，
example that it's kind of wide area
transactions are possible and also
特别是至少有一个打开她的系统蟑螂数据库使用了很多
specifically there's at least one opens
her system cockroach DB that uses a lot
明确使用大量设计激励用例的原因
of explicitly uses a lot of the design
the motivating use case the reason that
报纸说他们首先开始设计扳手的是
the paper says they first kind of
started the design spanner was that they
实际上已经有很多大型数据库系统，
were already had a actually they had
many big database systems and
Google，但他们的广告系统特别是数据短缺
Google but their advertising system in
particular the data was shorted over
许多不同的续集和BigTable数据库，并保持
many many distinct my sequel and
BigTable databases and maintaining that
分片只是一个笨拙，手动和耗时的过程
sharding was a just an awkward and
manual and time-consuming process in
此外，他们以前的广告数据库系统不允许
addition their previous advertising
database system didn't allow
跨多个交易的交易基本上比单个交易多
transactions that spanned more than a
single basically more than a single
服务器，但他们确实希望能够将数据更多地分发出去
server but they really wanted to be able
to have to spread their data out more
广泛地获得更好的性能，并进行多个交易
widely for better performance and to
have transactions over the multiple
广告数据库的数据分片显然是
shards of the data for their advertising
database apparently the workload was
以只读事务为主，我的意思是您可以在表6中看到它，其中
dominated by read-only transactions I
mean you can see this in table 6 where
有数十亿的只读交易，只有数百万
the there's billions of read-only
transactions and only millions of
读写交易，因此他们对交易的表现非常感兴趣
readwrite transactions so they're very
interested in the performance of
只读仅执行杂草的事务，并且显然还需要
read-only of transactions that only do
weeds and apparently they also required
强大的一致性，并且您知道特别是什么交易，因此它们
strong consistency and that you know
what transactions in particular so they
需要可序列化的交易，他们还需要外部一致性
wanted serializable transactions and
they also wanted external consistency
这意味着如果一项事务提交，然后完成
which means that if one transaction
commits and then after it finishes
提交另一笔交易开始第二笔交易需要看到任何
committing another transaction starts
the second transaction needs to see any
修改是由第一个完成的，并且这种外部一致性证明是
modification is done by the first and
this external consistency turns out to
对复制的数据很感兴趣，所以
be interesting with replicated data all
right so
拥有权只是服务器的物理布置的基本安排
ownage are just a basic arrangement sort
of physical arrangement of their servers
扳手使用它的服务器已分布在数据中心
that that spanner uses it has the its
servers are spread over data centers
大概是全世界，当然是整个美国
presumably all over the world certainly
all over the United States and each
数据被复制到多个数据中心，因此图表必须具有
piece of data is replicated at multiple
data centers so the diagrams got to have
多个数据中心让我们说真的有三个数据中心
multiple data centers let's say there's
there's three data centers really
还会有更多糟糕
there'd be many more oops
所以我们整日持不同意见，然后数据将其分
so we have all day
dissenters then the data shard it that
它被分解了，您可以想到它已被密钥和分解了
it's broken up you can think of it has
been being broken up by key into and
分散在许多服务器上，所以也许有一台服务器提供密钥启动
split over many servers so maybe there's
one server that serves keys starting
在此数据中心中以a或以B开头的另一个以此类推
with a in this data center or another
starting with B and so forth lots of
实际上，具有大量服务器的大量图表实际上每个数据中心在任何地方都具有
lots of charting with lots of servers in
fact every data center has on any piece
数据是在多个数据中心上复制的任何分片，因此
of data is any shard is replicated at
more than one data center so there's
将成为另一个副本的a键和B键的另一个副本，依此类推
going to be another copy another replica
of the a keys and the B keys and so on
在中心的第二天，又是另一个希望完全相同的副本
the second day in the center and yet
another hopefully identical copy of all
此数据位于第三个数据中心，此外每个数据中心都有多个
this data at the third data center in
addition each data center has multiple
客户或他们的扳手客户，以及这些客户在网络上的真实身份
clients or their clients of spanner and
what these clients really are as web
服务器，因此，如果我们普通人坐在网络浏览器前
servers so if our ordinary human beings
sitting in front of a web browser
连接到一些使用扳手的Google服务
connects to some Google service that
uses spanner
他们将连接到其中一个数据中心中的某些Web服务器，并且
they'll connect to some web server in
one of the data centers and that's going
成为这些扳手客户之一，可以复制
to be one of these one of these spanner
clients all right so that is replicated
复制实际上是由Paxos管理的，实际上，Paxos的变体
the replication is managed by Paxos in
fact that really a variant of Paxos that
有领导者，非常像我们都熟悉的木筏
has leaders and is really very much like
the raft that we're all familiar with
每个Paxos实例管理给定数据碎片的所有副本，因此
and each Paxos instance manages all the
replicas of a given shard of the data so
该分片的所有分片组成一个Paxos组，所有
this shard all the copies of this shard
form one Paxos group and all the
副本是这种碎片形式，其他包装是分组的，每个包装内都有
replicas are this shard form other packs
was group and within each these are
这些补丁实例是独立的，因为它自己的领导者运行自己的版本
these patches instances independent as
its own leader runs its own version of
礼包的诗歌实例是协议麻木，其原因是
the of the poem instance of the packs
was protocol numb and the reason for the
分片，对于每个分片的独立paxos实例，允许并行
sharding and for the independent paxos
instances per shard is to allow parallel
速度之快和大量并行吞吐量，因为数量众多
speed-up and a lot of parallel
throughput because there's a vast number
您知道的代表网络工作的客户数量
of clients you know which are
representing working on behalf of web
浏览器，所以通常并发
browsers so this huge number typically
of concurrent
请求，因此付出更大的代价将它们分成多个
requests and so it pays and more
immensely to split them up over multiple
碎片和多种并行运行的Paxos组
shards and multiple sort of Paxos groups
that are running in parallel okay and
您可能会想到，或者这些paxos组中的每一个都有一个领导，就像愤怒一样，所以
you can think of or each of these paxos
groups has a leader a lot like wrath so
也许这个分片的领导者不是数据是数据中心中的一个副本，并且
maybe the leader for this shard isn't
data is a replica in datacenter one and
该分片的领导者可能是副本和数据中心两个，依此类推
the leader for this shard might be the
replica and datacenter two and and so
并且您知道，这意味着如果您需要，如果客户需要
forth and you know so that means that if
you need to if a client needs to do a
它必须将其权利发送给其数据的分片的领导者
right it has to send that right to the
leader of the of the shard whose data it
需要仅用Raph编写这些Paxos实例，它们才是真正的
needs to write just with Raph these
Paxos instances are what they're really
做的是发送日志，领导者正在复制操作日志
doing is sending out a log the leader is
sort of replicating a log of operations
给所有跟随者，跟随者执行该日志，该日志用于数据
to all the followers and the followers
execute that log which is for data is
将被读取和写入，因此它将以相同的顺序执行所有日志
gonna be reads and writes so it executes
those logs all in the same order all
正确，所以这些设置的原因就是我提到的分片
right so the reason for these for this
setup the sharding as I mentioned for
在不同数据中心中的多个副本的吞吐量为两个
throughput the multiple copies in
different data centers is for two
原因之一是您想要复制和其他数据中心，以防一种数据
reasons one is you want copies and
different data centers in case one data
如果您知道整个城市的电源故障，则数据中心将失败
center fails if you know maybe you power
fails to the entire city the data
集中在地震，火灾或其他您想要的东西中
centers in or there's an earthquake or a
fire or something you'd like other
复制可能不会同时发生故障的其他数据中心
copies that other data centers that are
maybe not going to fail at the same time
然后您知道要为此付出代价，因为现在paxos协议
and then you know there's a price to pay
for that because now the paxos protocol
现在可能要长途交谈才能与关注者交谈，
now has to talk maybe over long
distances to talk to followers and
不同的数据中心在多个数据中心拥有数据的另一个原因是
different data centers the other reason
to have data in multiple data centers is
它可以让您在所有不同的客户端附近拥有数据副本
使用它，因此，如果您有一条可以在两个加利福尼亚州读取的数据
that use it so if you have a piece of
data that may be read in both California
在纽约，也许可以很高兴地在加利福尼亚州拥有一份该数据的副本
and New York maybe it's nice to have a
copy of that data one copy in California
一本在纽约的副本，因此阅读速度非常快，实际上很多
one copy in New York so that reads can
be very fast and indeed a lot of the
重点是时间是从本地读取
focus that
time is to make reads from the local the
最近的副本既快速又正确，最后是另一个有趣的交互
nearest replica both fast and correct
finally another interesting interaction
Paxos和多个数据中心之间的关系是
between Paxos and multiple data centers
is that
paxos lie craft仅需要多数才能复制日志条目，并且
paxos lie craft only requires a majority
in order to replicate a log entry and
继续，这意味着如果有一个慢速，遥远或不稳定的数据中心，
proceed and that means if there's one
slow or distant or flaky data center the
Paxil系统可以保持协调并接受新请求，即使一个数据
Paxil system can keep chugging along and
accepting new requests even if one data
中心正在缓慢，好吧，这样的安排
center is is being slow all right so
with this arrangement there's a couple
论文必须克服的一大挑战是他们真的想阅读
of big challenges that paper has to bite
off one is they really want to do reads
来自本地数据中心，但是因为他们使用的是Paxos，而且因为Paxos
from local data centers but because
they're using Paxos and because Paxos
只要求每个日志条目都以多数复制，这意味着
only requires each log entry to be
replicated on a majority that means a
少数副本可能滞后并且可能没有看到最新数据
minority of the replicas may be lagging
and may not have seen the latest data
这是由paxos提交的，这意味着如果我们允许客户阅读
that's been committed by paxos and that
means that if we allow clients to read
从本地副本以提高速度，他们可能正在读取过时的数据，如果它们
from the local replicas for speed they
may be reading out-of-date data if their
副本恰好在少数族群中，没有看到最新更新，因此
replica happens to be in the minority
that didn't see the latest updates so
他们必须这样做，因为他们需要正确性，他们需要这个
they have to since they're requiring
correctness they're requiring this
外部一致性的想法，即每次读取都可以看到他们最新的数据
external consistency idea that every
read see the most up-to-date data they
必须采用某种方式来处理本地副本的可能性
have to have some way of dealing with
the possibility that the local replicas
可能滞后于他们必须处理的另一个问题是，交易可能
may be lagging another issue they have
to deal with is that a transaction may
涉及多个分片，因此涉及多个paxos组，因此您可能
involve multiple shards and therefore
multiple paxos groups so you may be
读取或写入单个交易可能是读取或写入多个交易
reading or writing a single transaction
may be reading or writing multiple
数据库中存储在多个分片和多个Paxil中的记录
records in the database that are stored
in multiple shards and multiple Paxil
脚本，所以这些必须是我们，我们需要分布式事务，所以我
scripts so those have to be we need
distributed transactions okay so I'm
将会解释交易的工作方式
going to explain how the transactions
work that's going to be the kind of
演讲者的重点实际上是实现读写交易
focus of the lecture spanner actually
beats implements readwrite transactions
与只读交易大不相同，所以让我从您的
quite differently from read-only
transactions so let me start with your
如此之多的传统读写事务之美
beauty of readwrite transactions which
are so have a lot more conventional in
他们的设计还不错，所以第一次读写交易让我提醒您
their design alright so first readwrite
transactions let me just remind you at a
交易看起来像这样，让我们​​只选择一个简单的交易
transaction looks like so let's just
choose a simple one that's like
模仿银行转帐，所以我是其中的一台客户计算机
mimicking bank transfer so I'm one of
those client machines a client of
扳手，您将运行一些代码，您将运行此事务代码，代码会说哦
spanner you'd run some code you run this
transaction code the code would say oh
我正在开始交易，然后我会说哦，我想读写
I'm beginning a transaction and then I
would say oh I want to read and write
这些记录，所以也许您在数据库记录X中有一个银行余额，我们想要
these records so maybe you have a bank
balance in database record X and we want
你知道增加和增加这个银行余额减少你的银行
to you know increment and increase this
bank balance and decrease y's bank
余额，哦，交易到此结束，现在客户希望
balance and oh that's the end of the
transaction and now the client hopes the
数据库将关闭并提交
database will go off and commit that
好吧，所以我想追溯所有必须发生的步骤
alright so I want to trace through all
the steps that that have to happen in
为了使扳手执行此读写事务，因此首先
order to in order for spanner to execute
this read write transaction so first of
一个数据中心中有一个客户正在推动这项交易
all there's a client in one of the data
centers that's driving this transaction
所以我在这里画这个客户让我们想象一下x和y在不同的位置
so I'll draw this client here let's
imagine that x and y are on different
分片，因为那是有趣的情况，而那些分片
shards since that's the that's the
interesting case and that those shards
两个分片中的每一个都在三个不同的数据中心中复制，因此我们知道
each of the two shards is replicated in
three different data centers so know we
我们在这里拥有三个数据中心，每个数据中心都有一台服务器，
got our three data centers here and at
each data center there's a server that
我将为保留行为的碎片的副本编写x
I'm just going to write x for the
replicas of the shard that's holding act
使用这三个服务器微调器的x和y的银行余额一次
with the bank balance for x and y for
the these three servers spinner once
两阶段提交只是为了完全承受我们的两阶段提交和两阶段
two-phase commit just to totally stand
our two-phase commit and two phase
几乎完全按照上周603的读数中所述进行锁定
locking almost exactly as described in
the reading from last week from the 603
三本教科书，其巨大的区别在于代替了参与者和
three textbook and the huge difference
is that instead of the participants and
交易管理者是个人计算机，参与者是
the transaction manager being individual
computers the participants in the
Paxos复制了事务方式管理器
transaction manner manager are Paxos
replicated
多组服务器以提高容错能力，这意味着提醒
groups of servers for increased fault
tolerance so that means just to remind
你说该碎片存储X的碎片的三个副本，
you that the shard the three replicas of
the shard that stores X it's a really
应用访问组与这三个副本的Y相同，我们可以想象
app access group same with these three
replicas strong Y and we'll just imagine
对于这三台服务器中的每台服务器来说，它都是领导者，所以我们说
that for each of these one of the three
servers is the leader so let's say the
服务器和数据中心2是Paxos的领导者，X是分片，
server and data center 2 is the Paxos
leader for the X is shard and the
仆人说您是Paxos的领导者，您很清楚，所以第一个
servant is saying one is the Paxos
leader for y sharp okay so the first
发生的事情是硬币选择了唯一的交易ID
thing that happens is that the coin
picks a unique transaction ID which is
将被携带在所有这些消息上，以便系统知道
going to be carried on all these
messages so that the system knows that
所有不同的操作都与单个交易相关联
all the different operations are
associated with a single transaction the
客户端的第一件事必须是这样，尽管代码看起来像
first thing that does the client has to
be so despite the way the code looks
它在其中读取和写入X，然后实际上以某种方式读取一些写入Y
where it reads and writes X then read
some write Y in fact the way the code
必须组织交易代码，必须先进行所有读取，
has transaction code has to be organized
it has to do all its reads first and
然后在最后，基本上同时将所有写入作为
then at the very end do all the writes
at the same time essentially as part of
提交，以便客户做得很好，这表明它是为了
the commit so the clients to do good
reads it turns out that it in order to
保持锁定，因为就像您上周每次阅读6:53一样
maintain locks since just as as in last
week's 6:53 reading every time you read
或写一个数据项，负责它的服务器必须关联一个
or write a data item the server
responsible for it has to associate a
用该数据项锁定锁，将保持读取锁和扳手的锁
lock with that data item the locks are
maintained the read locks and spanner
仅在Paxos领导者中维护，因此当客户交易想要
maintain only in the Paxos leader so
when the client transaction wants to
读取访问权限将读取的X请求发送给X的领导者，而该领导者是分片的，并且该领导者
read access sends a read X request to
the leader of X is shard and that leader
的分片返回x的当前值，当然，如果
of the shard returns the current value
of x plus sets a lock on X of course if
锁已经设置好了，您将直到任何时候都不会响应客户端
the locks already set then you won't
respond to the client until whatever
当前已锁定数据的事务通过提交释放锁
transaction currently has the data
locked releases the lock by committing
然后是该分片的领导者，因为将x的值返回给客户
and then the leader for that shard since
back the value of x to client the client
这次需要读Y很幸运，因为
needs to read Y got lucky this time
because the
假设像数据中心的客户一样，本地数据中心的领导者
assuming like clients in data center one
the leaders in the local data center so
这将使读取速度更快，从而将税金锁定在Y上
this reads gonna be a lot faster that
reads sets the lock on Y in the taxes
领导，然后返回好吧，现在所有读取的客户
leader and then returns okay's now the
clients on all the reads it does
内部计算并弄清楚想要做什么值的写入
internal computations and figures out
the writes that wants to do what values
想写x和y，所以现在客户端要发送更新的
wants to write to x and y and so now the
clients going to send out the updated
要写入的记录的值，并且一次完成所有操作
values for the records that it wants to
write and it does this all at once at
交易即将结束的第一件事
the end towards the end of the
transaction so the first thing it does
是从那些分组中选择一个作为交易
is it chooses one of the packs those
groups to act as the transaction
协调员，因为它提前选择了我们，因此会发送
coordinator and as it chooses us in
advance and it's gonna send out the
Paxos组将充当交易的身份
identity of the which Paxos group is
going to act as the transaction
协调器，让我们假设它选择了这个Paxos组，我已经拆分了一个双框
coordinator so let's assume it chooses
this Paxos group i've split a double box
这里说的是，这台服务器不仅是其Paxos组的领导者，而且还是
here to say that not only is this server
the leader of its Paxos group it's also
充当此事务的事务协调者，然后客户端发送
acting as transaction coordinator for
this transaction then the client sends
列出要写入的更新值，以便发送写入
out the updated values that it wants to
write so it's going to send a write
在此处额外写入X请求，并带有新值和
extra write X request here with a new
value and the identity of the
交易协调员，当每个Paxos领导者获得每个书面价值时
transaction coordinator when each the
Paxos leader for each written value
收到写请求，它向其关注者发送一条准备消息，并
receives the write request it sends out
a prepare message to its followers and
将其输入到Paxos日志中，以便我用P代表它进入paxos
gets that into the Paxos log so that
I'll represent that by P into the paxos
记录日志，因为它会承诺能够到达，这是一个错误的词
log because it's gonna commit to being
able to come it's the wrong word it's
承诺能够执行尚未崩溃的交易
promising to be able to carry out this
transaction that it hasn't crashed for
例子，并失去了锁，所以它发出此准备消息日志
example and lost its locks so it sends
out this prepare message logs the
当收到来自大多数用户的回复时，通过paxos准备消息
prepare message through paxos when it
gets a majority of responses from the
追随者，那么这个契约是领导者向交易发送“是”
followers then this pacts was leader
sends a yes to the transaction
协调员说，是的，我很有希望能够履行我的职责。
coordinator saying yes I am a promising
to be able to carry out my part of the
YV趋势权，从概念上讲
trend
right to Y V and notionally the
交易中看到客户还判该值被咬-为什么-
transaction see the client also
sentenced the value to be bitten - why -
为什么paxos领导者和充当paxos领导者的服务器发出准备
why's paxos leader and this server
acting as paxos leader sends out prepare
消息给他的追随者并记录下来，这会影响到
messages to his followers and logs it
impacts those weights for the
来自大多数人的感谢，然后您可以将其视为Paxos
acknowledgments from a majority and then
you can think of it as as the Paxos
领导者发送同一台机器上的交易协调器
leaders sending the transaction
coordinator which is on the same machine
也许是同一程序，是的，赞成票，是的，我可以提交，所以当
maybe the same program a yes vote saying
yes I can I can commit okay so when the
交易协调员得到领导者的不同回应
transaction coordinator gets responses
from all the different from the leaders
涉及此事务的所有不同分片中的所有分片（如果它们
of all the different shards whose data
is involved in this transaction if they
所有人都说是的，那么交易协调员可以提交，否则
all said yes then the transaction
coordinator can commit otherwise it
不能假设它决定在此时进行提交
can't let's assume it decides to commit
at that point the transaction
协调员向paxos追随者发送一条提交消息，说看
coordinator sends out to the paxos
followers a commit message saying look
请记住，我们永久在交易日志中
please remember that permanently in the
transaction log that we're committing
这笔交易还告诉其他PAC的领导人
this transaction and it also tells the
leaders of the other PACs those groups
参与交易，那么他们也可以提交，所以现在
involved in the transaction then they
can commit as well and so now this
领导者在提交后立即向其关注者发送提交消息
leader sends out commit messages to his
followers as well as soon as the commits
是
are
事务协调器可能不会将提交消息发送到
the transaction coordinator probably
doesn't send out the commit message to
其他分片，直到它在日志中被安全地提交为止，以便事务
the other shards until it's committed as
safe in the log so that the transaction
提交这些内容后，不保证协调员不会忘记其决定
coordinator is not guaranteed not to
forget its decision once commits these
提交消息分别提交到不同分片的paxos日志中
commit messages are committed into the
paxos logs of the different shards each
这些分片中的一部​​分实际上可以执行放置书面数据的权利
of those shards can actually execute the
rights that is place the written data
并释放数据项上的锁，以便其他事务可以使用它们
and release the locks on the data items
so that other transactions can use them
然后进行交易，因此首先请随时提出问题
and then the transactions over so first
of all please feel free to ask questions
如果通过举手示意，如果您有疑问，那么有几点要点
if by raising your hand a few if you
have questions ok so there's some points
观察到目前为止的设计，该设计仅涵盖了
to observe about the design so far which
is only covered the readwrite aspect of
事务之一是确保可串行性的锁定
transactions one is that it's that the
locking that is insuring serializability
这是两个事务冲突的原因，因为它们使用的数据相同
that is of two transactions conflict
because they use the same data one has
完全等待其他释放锁之后才能继续操作，因此
to completely wait for the other
releases locks before it can proceed so
因此，扳手使用完全标准的两相锁定，以便
it's using so spanners using completely
standard two-phase locking in order to
获得可序列化性和完全标准的两阶段提交以获取
get serializability and completely
standard two-phase commit to get
在分布式交易中，两阶段犯下了广泛的仇恨，因为如果
distributed transactions the two-phase
commits widely hated because if the
事务协调器应该比任何事务失败或变得不可访问
transaction coordinator should fail or
become unreachable than any transactions
它一直在无限期地管理区块，直到事务协调员回来
it was managing block indefinitely until
the transaction coordinator comes back
起来，并用锁锁起来，所以人们通常都非常
up and they block with locks help so
people have been in general very
在现实世界中不愿使用两阶段提交，因为它阻塞了扳手
reluctant to use two-phase commit in the
real world because it's blocking spanner
通过复制事务管理器来解决此问题
solves this by replicating the
transaction manager the transaction
管理器本身是Paxos复制状态机，所以它所做的一切
manager itself is a Paxos replicated
state machine so everything it does like
例如，请记住是否已将其提交到副本中
for example remember whether it's
committed or not is replicated into the
paxos记录日志，因此即使领导者正在管理
paxos log so if the leader here fails
even though it was managing the
交易，因为它是木筏复制的两个
transaction because it's raft replicated
either of these two
复制品可以生机勃勃地接管领导，也可以接管
replicas can spring to life take over
leadership and also take over being the
交易经理，他们的法律将是交易经理
transaction manager and they'll have in
their law it's the transaction manager
决定承诺任何接管的领导者都会看到承诺，这是日志，
decided to commit any leader that takes
over will see a commitment it's log and
然后能够立即告诉另一个参与者
be able to then tell the other right
away tell the other participants and
两阶段提交，看起来哦，此事务已提交，所以这
two-phase commit that look oh this
transaction was committed so this
有效地消除了可以阻止的两阶段提交问题
effectively eliminates the problem a
two-phase commit that it can block with
如果发生故障，则持有锁，这确实很重要，因为此问题
locks held if there's a failure this is
a really big deal because this problem
基本上使两阶段提交对于其他情况完全不可接受
basically makes two-phase commit
otherwise completely unacceptable for
任何具有很多可能会导致其他部分失效的大型系统
any sort of large-scale system that has
a lot of parts that might fail the other
还要注意的另一件事是，在此中有大量消息
another thing to note is that there's a
huge amount of messages on in this
此处的图表，这意味着其中许多是跨数据中心的，
diagram here and that means that many of
them are across data centers and said
在分片之间或客户端之间传递的一些消息
the some of these messages that go
between the shards or between a client
一个碎片，另一个数据中心的领导者可能需要花费几毫秒的时间
and a shard whose leaders in another
data center may take many milliseconds
在一个您知道计算需要纳秒的世界中，这是
and in a world in which you know
computations take nanoseconds this is
本质上相当严峻的支出，实际上您可以从表中看到
essentially pretty grim expense and
indeed you can see that from in table
六和表六（如果您查看的话）描述了扳手的性能
six and table six if you look at it it's
describing the performance of a spanner
部署，其中不同副本位于联合国的不同侧
deployment where the different replicas
are on different sides of the United
我位于东西海岸的国家，大约需要一百毫秒
States I east and west coast and it
takes about a hundred milliseconds to do
完成涉及不同副本的交易
complete a transaction where the
different replicas involved are on
不同的外套需要大量的时间，大约是十分之一秒
different coats that's a huge amount of
time it's a tenth of a second there's
也许没有看起来那么糟糕，因为系统的吞吐量
maybe not quite as bad as it may seem
because the throughput of the system
因为它经过分片，并且可以在其中运行许多无冲突的事务
since it's sharded and it can run a lot
of non conflicting transactions in
并行吞吐量可能非常高，但是它们的延迟对于单个
parallel the throughput may be very hard
high but their delay for individual
交易非常重要，我的意思是一百毫秒可能有点
transactions very significant I mean a
hundred milliseconds is maybe somewhat
少于人类所注意到的，但是如果您必须做几个
less than a human is going to notice but
if you have to do a couple of them to
只是说要生成网页或进行人工指导就可以了
just say generate a webpage or carry out
a human instruction it's starting to be
你注意到你开始烦恼的时间
amount of time whoops
you noticeable start to be bothering
另一方面，我觉得很麻烦
bothersome
on the other hand for I think I suspect
从扳手的许多用途来看，所有副本都可能在同一城市或
from many uses of spanner all the
replicas might be in in the same city or
在整个城镇中，它们是您可以在表中看到的更快的时间
sort of across town and they're the much
faster times that you can see in Table
三个与地球表有关。三个表明它可以完成
three are relevant in the Earth's Table
three shows that it can complete
您知道，数据中心就在附近的交易
transactions where the data centers are
nearby in all right you know I think
是14毫秒而不是100毫秒，所以不是很
it's 14 milliseconds instead of 100
milliseconds so that's not quite so that
但是，这些读/写事务的速度足够慢，以至于我们会
nevertheless these read/write
transactions are slow enough that we'd
如果可能的话，我想避免花这笔钱，这将使我们
like to avoid the expense if we possibly
can so that's going to take us to
只读事务，事实证明，如果您不写，那就是
read-only transactions it turns out that
if you're not writing that is if you
事先知道交易中的所有操作都是
know in advance that all of the
operations in a transaction are
保证会被读取，然后扳手的速度就会大大提高
guaranteed to be reads then spanner has
a much faster much more streamlined much
执行只读事务的消息量较小的消息密集型方案
less massive message intensive scheme
for executing read-only transactions
好的，所以只读事务开始一个新主题，即只读事务
okay so so read-only transactions start
a new topic the reader only transactions
尽管他们依赖于读写事务中的某些信息，但仍能正常工作
work although they rely on some
information from readwrite transactions
设计与读取扳手中的读写事务完全不同的设计
to designs quite different from the read
of the readwrite transactions in spanner
消除了两大成本，并且它的只读事务设计消除了
eliminates two big costs and it's
read-only transaction design eliminates
首先存在的两个成本是读写交易，因为我
two of the costs that were present and
readwrite transactions first of all as I
提到它从本地副本读取，因此如果您有一个副本，只要
mentioned it reads from local replicas
and so if you have a replica as long as
客户需要本地交易的DVD的副本
there's a replica the DVD the client
needs the transaction needs in the local
您可以从该数据中心读取数据并从该本地副本中读取数据
data center you can do the read and from
that local replica which may take a
与之对话的一小部分，而不是数十个
small fraction of a millisecond to talk
to instead of maybe dozens of
毫秒，如果您必须去越野，以便可以从本地读取
milliseconds if you have to go cross
country so it can read from local
副本，但是您再次知道这里存在的危险是任何给定的副本
replicas but node you know again a
danger here is that any given replicas
可能不是最新的，所以必须有一个故事
may not be up-to-date so there has to be
a story for that
另一个大的节省和只读设计是它不使用
and the other big savings and the
read-only design is that it doesn't use
锁定它不使用两阶段提交，我的意思是不需要事务
locks it doesn't use two-phase commit I
mean that doesn't need a transaction
经理，这使跨数据中心或跨数据中心之类的东西无效
manager and this the voids things like
cross data center or inter data center
给领导人的消息，因为不仅没有锁，
messages to PACs those leaders and
because no locks are taken out not only
这样可以使只读事务更快，但可以避免
does that make the read-only
transactions faster but it avoids
减慢只读读写事务，因为它们不必
slowing down read only read write
transactions because they don't have to
只读事务持有的锁的费率现在我的意思是
rate for locks held by read-only
transactions now I mean just to kind of
预览为什么这对他们很重要表3和6显示了十倍的延迟
preview why this is important to them
tables 3 & 6 show a ten times latency
与读写事务相比，只读事务有所改进，因此
improvement for read-only transactions
compared to readwrite transactions so
主要的唯一设计是提交因素使延迟增加了十倍，而且少得多
the main only design is submit factor
ten boost in latency and much less
几乎可以肯定，复杂性也将带来更大的吞吐量，这也是巨大的挑战
complexity is almost certainly far more
throughput as well and the big challenge
将会如何平方您知道的交易确实不会做很多
is going to be how to square the you
know really transactions don't do a lot
需要安静的事物，我们不重写事务来获取
of things that were quiet required and
we don't rewrite transactions to get
序列化功能，所以我们需要找到一种求平方的方法
serialize ability so we need to find a
need to find a way to kind of square
正确性提高了效率，所以实际上有两个
this increased efficiency with
correctness and so there's really two
他们想要进行只读事务的主要正确性约束
main correctness constraints that they
wanted to have read-only transactions
首先要说的是，他们喜欢仍然需要进行的所有交易
imposed the first is that they like all
transactions they still need to be
可序列化，这意味着即使只是回顾
serializable and what that means is that
even though just a review even though
系统可以并行并行执行事务，结果
the system may execute transactions
concurrently in parallel the results
一堆并发事务必须同时产生两种
that a bunch of concurrent transactions
must yield both in terms of sort of
返回给客户端的值以及对数据库的修改
values that they return to the client
and modifications to the database the
一堆并发事务的结果必须与某些
results of a bunch of concurrent
transactions must be the same as some
一次或串行执行这些事务，并且只读
one at a time or serial execution of
those transactions and for read-only
交易本质上意味着的是
transactions what that essentially means
is that the an entire all the reads of a
只读交易必须有效地整齐地放在
read-only transaction must effectively
fit neatly between all the rights of a
一堆可以被视为先行的交易
bunch of transactions that can be viewed
as going before it
并且它一定不能看到我们正在交易的任何权利
and and it must not see any of the
rights of the transactions that we're
紧随其后去查看，因此我们需要一种适合所有阅读方式的方法
going to view as it's going after it so
we need a way to sort of fit to read all
事务的只读只读
the reads of a transaction read-only
transaction kind of neatly between
很好地写交易，这是本文讨论的另一大障碍
readwrite transactions well the other
big constraint that the paper talks
关于他们想要外部一致性，这意味着什么
about is that they want external
consistency and what this means it's
实际上等同于我们在此之前看到的线性化能力
actually equivalent to linearise ability
that we've seen before what this really
意思是，如果一个事务提交完成，另一个事务提交
means is that if one transaction commits
finishes committing and another
交易在第一笔交易实时完成后开始，然后
transaction starts after the first
transaction completed in real time then
第二笔交易需要查看第一笔交易的权利
the second transaction is required to
see the rights done by the first
交易的另一种表达方式是，交易甚至是只读的
transaction another way of putting that
is that transactions even read-only
事务不应看到过时的数据，并且是否存在来自
transactions should not see stale data
and if there's a committed write from a
已完成的交易比只读交易先于
completed transaction that's prior to
the readonly transaction prior to the
只读事务的开始，需要只读事务才能看到
start of the read-only transaction the
read-only transaction is required to see
好的，所以实际上这两者都不是特别重要
that right ok so this is actually none
of neither of these is particularly
令人惊讶，但是像我的续集之类的标准数据库还是可以的
surprising but standard databases like
my sequel or something for example can
被配置为提供这种一致性，因此在某种程度上
be configured to provide this kind of
consistency so in a way it's sort of the
一致性，如果您不了解的话，这就是一致性
consistency that if you didn't know
better this is exactly the consistency
您会期望一个简单的系统，并且在您
that you would expect of a
straightforward system and in the you
知道有它，但是它使程序员生活
know
have it but it makes programmers lives
这样就更容易产生正确答案，否则您就不会
it makes it much easier to produce
correct answers in otherwise you don't
具有这种一致性，则程序员负责
have this kind of consistency then the
programmers are responsible for kind of
围绕数据库可能提供的异常进行编程，所以就像
programming around whatever anomalies
the database may provide so this is like
一个夜晚，这是正确性的黄金标准
a night this is sort of the gold
standard of correctness
好吧，让我来谈一谈如何仅交易有效
okay so let's I want to gonna talk about
how we'd only transactions work it's a
有点复杂的故事，所以我想首先谈的是
bit of a complex story so I think what
I'd like to talk about first is to just
考虑如果我们绝对做最愚蠢的事情会发生什么，
consider what would happen if we did
just absolutely the stupidest thing and
只读事务没有做任何特殊的事情来实现一致性
had the read-only transactions not do
anything special to achieve consistency
但只要读取数据的最新副本，以便每次我只读取
but just read the very latest copy of
the data so every time I read only
事务会读取，我们可以让它查看本地副本并
transaction does a read we could just
have it look at the local replicas and
找到当前数据的最新副本，那将非常
find the current most up-to-date copy of
the data and that would be very
直接的非常低的开销，所以我们需要了解为什么它不起作用
straightforward very low overhead so we
need to understand why that doesn't work
为了这样，所以为什么不读取最新值呢？
in order so this is a so why not read
the just a the latest value and so maybe
我们将想象该事务是只读取x和y的事务
we'll imagine that the transaction is a
transaction that simply reads x and y
并以只读方式将其打印为财务文件我将以Y打印我以X逗号打印
and prints them finance read-only I'm
going to print Y I'll just print X comma
ÿ
Y
好的，所以我想给你看一个例子，其中阅读
okay so all I want to show you an
example of a situation in which read
进行此交易只是简单地将最新价值产生为不正确
having this transaction is just simply
be the latest value yields incorrect not
无法序列化的结果，因此假设我们有三个正在运行的事务t1 t2 t3
not serializable results so suppose we
have three transactions running t1 t2 t3
t3将是我们的事务t1和t2或我们重写的事务
t3 is going to be our transaction t1 and
t2 or transactions that are our rewrite
所以说t1正确的性别和权利为什么然后提交和
transactions so let's say that t1 right
sex and rights why and then commits and
你知道也许这是银行转账操作，所以它在转账
you know maybe it's a bank transfer
operation so it's transferring money
从X到Y，我们正在打印x和y，因为我们正在对银行进行审计
from X to Y and we're printing x and y
because we're doing an audit of the bank
尝试确保它没有亏钱，让我们想象一下交易2
try to make sure it hasn't lost money
let's imagine that transaction 2 also
在余额x和y之间进行另一次转移，然后提交，现在我们有了
does another transfer between balances x
and y and then commits and now we have
我们的交易交易t3需要读取x和y，所以它将有一个
our transaction transaction t3 it needs
to read x and y so it's gonna have a
读X假设说X的读发生在这个时间点，所以我
read of X let's say the read of X
happens at this point in time and so I'm
我绘制这些图的方式是实时移动到右侧
the way I'm drawing these diagrams is
that real time moves to the right wall
您在手表上看到的时钟时间向右移动，因此X的读数
clock time time you'd see on your watch
moves to the right so the read of X
在事务1完成之后，事务2开始之前在这里发生
happens here after transaction 1
completes before transaction 2 starts
假设T 3在速度较慢的计算机上运行，​​因此它只能设法发出
and let's say T 3 is running on a slow
computer so it only manages to issue the
读Y的时间很晚，所以交易的方式是交易3
read of Y much later so the way this is
gonna play out is that transaction 3
将看到t1写入的Y值，但t2写入的x值
will see the Y value that t1 wrote but
the x value that t2 wrote
假设它使用简单地读取最新值的可疑程序
assuming it uses this dubious procedure
of simply reading the latest value
在数据库中，因此无法序列化，因为我们知道
that's in the database and so this is
not serializable because well we know
可能存在的任何串行订单都必须带有t1，然后是t2，只有
that any serial order that could exist
must have t1 followed by t2 there's only
2个地方的牙齿里卡去了，所以t3可以去这里
2 places teeth rica go so t3 could go
here
之所以不适合此处，是因为如果t3在同等顺序中排第二
can't fit here because if t3 was second
in the equivalent serial order then it
在t2之后不应该看到权利，而在t2之后应该看到Y的值
shouldn't see rights by t2 which comes
after it should see the value of Y
t1产生的值，但没有写入，因此看到t2产生的t3值，因此
produced by t1 but it doesn't write it
see the value produced by t3 by t2 so
这不是等效的，此序列订单不会产生相同的结果
this is not an equivalent this serial
order wouldn't produce the same results
我们唯一可以使用的另一个是这个序列订单可以得到的
the only other one available to us is
this one this serial order would get the
与t3实际产生的y相同，但是如果这是串行的
same value for y that t3 actually
produced but if this was the serial
顺序，那么t3应该已经看到了t2写入的值，但实际上看到了
order then t3 should have seen the value
written by t2 but it actually saw the
t1编写的有价值的代码，因此此执行一次等效于任何一次执行
valuable written by t1 so this execution
is not equivalent to any one at a time
灼热的顺序，所以这就像读的东西有问题
searing the order so this is like
there's something broken about reads
只需读取最新值，就可以知道您不知道该怎么做
simply reading the latest value so we
know that doesn't work you know what
我们真正在寻找的当然是我们的交易
we're really looking for of course is
that either the our our transaction
或者在此时读取两个值，或者在两个时间读取两个值
either reads the both values at this
point in time or it reads both values at
在这个时间点还可以，所以将我们的口味扩展到这一点的方法是
this point in time okay so the approach
that span our taste to this it's a
有点复杂，第一个大创意是现有的创意
somewhat complex the first big idea is
an existing idea
这就是快照隔离
it's called snapshot isolation
我要描述的方式是让我们想象一下
and the way I'm gonna describe this is
that let's imagine that all the
涉及的计算机具有同步时钟，这就是您知道它们都有一个
computers involved had synchronized
clocks that is you know they all have a
时钟所使用的时钟会产生我们或墙上时钟的时间，例如oh在143
clock the clock wields yields us or wall
clock time like oh it's 143 in the
2020年4月7日下午，这就是我们所说的挂钟时间
afternoon on April 7th 2020 so that's
what we mean by a wall clock time a time
因此假设所有计算机都假设即使这不是真的
so it's assumed that all the computers
assume even though this isn't true that
所有涉及的计算机都已同步时间，让我们
all the computers involved have
synchronized times furthermore let's
想象每个事务都在特定的时间分配了时间戳
imagine that every transaction is
assigned a particular time a time stamp
和
and
为其壁钟添加时间戳记，这些时间取自这些同步时钟
time stamps their wall clocks times
taken from these synchronized clocks for
读写事务，它的时间戳就是为此
readwrite transaction its timestamp is
I'm going to say just for this for this
简化的设计是提交时的实时
simplified design is the real time at at
the commit
并在事务管理器启动时读取或
and for read for a or at the time at
which the transaction manager starts the
提交，对于只读事务，时间戳等于所有的开始时间
commit and for read-only transaction the
timestamp is equal to the start time all
没错，所以每个人都有时间，我们将设计我们的系统
right so every turns out
time and we're gonna design our system
或快照隔离系统gets被设计为好像要获取
or a snapshot isolation system gets is
designed to execute as if to get the
就像所有事务都按时间戳顺序执行一样，所以我们
same results as if all the transactions
had executed in timestamp order so we're
将为每个交易分配一个时间戳，然后我们
going to assign the transactions each
transaction a timestamp and then we're
将安排执行，以便事务获得结果，就好像
going to arrange the executions so that
the transactions gets the results as if
他们以该顺序执行，因此考虑到时间戳，我们需要
they had executed in that order so given
the timestamps we sort of need to have
一个可以轻松实现时间戳和
an implementation that will kind of
easily honor the timestamps and
基本上，您知道向每个事务显示其存在的数据类型
basically you know show each transaction
the data sort of as it existed at its
时间戳没问题，因此它适用于只读事务的方式是
timestamp okay so the way that this
works for read-only transactions is that
每个副本在存储数据时实际上具有多个版本
each replica when it stores data it
actually has multiple versions of the
数据，所以我们有一个多版本数据库，每个数据库记录都有
data so we have a multiple version
database every database record has you
知道也许已经写过几次了，它有一个单独的副本
know maybe if it's been written a couple
times it has a separate copy of that
记录每次写入的时间
record for each of the times it's been
written
其中每一个都与编写的事务的时间戳相关联
each one of them associated with the
timestamp of the transaction that wrote
然后是基本策略，即当交易
it and then the basic strategies that
read only transactions when they when a
只读事务进行读取，它已经为其自身分配了时间戳
read-only transaction does a read it's
already allocated itself a timestamp
当它开始时，因此它伴随着其时间戳的读取请求和
when it started and so it accompanies
its read request with its timestamp and
任何存储数据副本的服务器
the whatever server that stores the
replicas of the data that the
交易需求，它将进入其多版本数据库并查找
transaction needs it's going to look
into its multi version database and find
被要求的记录是最短的时间
the record that's being asked for that
as the highest time that's still less
比只读事务指定的时间戳大，因此意味着
than the timestamp specified by the
read-only transaction so that means to
是唯一的事务类型，它看到的是截至目前为止的数据
be the only transaction sort of sees
data that is data as of the time as up
现在是时间jozin时间戳了，所以这是用于快照隔离的想法
it's time jozin timestamp okay so this
is for this snapshot isolation idea
适用于只读事务或扳手将其用于只读
works for read-only transactions or
spanner uses it for read-only
事务微调器用户仍使用两阶段锁定和两阶段提交
transactions spinner users still uses
two-phase locking and two-phase commit
用于读写事务，因此读写事务分配
for readwrite transactions and so the
readwrite transactions allocate
时间戳为他们自己的承诺时间，但除了他们在
timestamps for themselves a commit time
but other than that they work in the
带锁和两阶段提交的通常方式是只读
usual way with locks and two-phase
commit where's the read-only
事务访问数据库中的多个版本，并获取
transactions access multiple versions in
the database and get the version that's
您知道由撰写的带有时间戳记
you know written by the has the
timestamp
最高，仍低于只读交易次数的日期
that's highest that's still less than
the read-only transactions times date
而这将使我们得到的是您知道只读事务
and where this is going to get us is
that you know read-only transactions
将以较低的时间戳看到读写事务的所有权利，并且
will see all the rights of readwrite
transactions with lower timestamps and
没有具有更高的tyst时间戳的读/写事务的权利
none of the rights of read/write
transactions with higher tyst timestamps
好的，那么如何隔离我们的示例
okay so how would
isolation work out for our example
我以前在这里遇到的例子，在此之前我们发生了串行故障
example that I had here before in which
we had a failure of serial
可序列化，因为在读取值之前先读取事务
serializability because reading
transaction read before I read values
不在其他两个之间的交易是光明的交易，所以这是一个
that were not between any two other be
bright transactions okay so this is an
我们的示例，但具有快照隔离功能，我向您展示此内容以表明
our example but with snapshot isolation
I'm showing you this to show that the
快照隔离技术解决了我们导致只读事务的问题
snapshot isolation technique solves our
problem causes the read-only transaction
可以序列化，所以我们又有了这两个读写事务t1和
to be serializable so again we have
these two readwrite transactions t1 and
t2，我们的交易是只读交易t1和t2，
t2 and we have our transaction that's a
read-only transaction t1 and t2 right as
在他们写之前，他们承诺但现在
before they write and they commit but
now
他们在提交时间之前分配自己的时间戳，所以除了
they're allocating themselves timestamps
as of the commit time so in addition to
使用双面命令和两阶段锁定这些读/写事务
using two-faced command and two-phase
locking these read/write transactions
分配一个时间戳，让我们想象一下在提交T时
allocate a timestamp so let's imagine
that at the time of the commit T one
看着时钟，发现时间是十点，我要用十点的时间
looked at the clock and saw that it the
time was ten I'm gonna use times of ten
还有二十点什么，但是你知道你应该把时间想象成真实的时间
and twenty and whatnot but you know you
should imagine times as being real times
就像某天早晨四点，所以我们说T人看到了
like four o'clock in the morning on a
given day so let's say that T one sees
提交的时间为10，T 2看到提交时间为
the time as 10 when it committed and T 2
sees that the commit time the time was
20，所以我要在@符号后的时间戳中选择这些事务，然后
20 so I'm gonna write these transactions
chosen timestamp after the @ sign then
我们存储系统将要存储的数据库存储系统
the database storage systems the span
our storage systems are going to store
当事务1进行写操作时，它们将存储一种新的
when transaction 1 does its writes
they're gonna store a new sort of not
而不是覆盖当前值，他们只是要添加一个新副本
instead of overwriting in the current
value they're just gonna add a new copy
带有时间戳的记录，因此数据库将
of this record with the timestamp so
it's gonna the database is going to
储存一条新记录，这表示x在时间10的值等于
store away a new record this says the
value of x at time 10 is whatever it
碰巧是说9在时间10的记录Y的值是C 11也许我们是
happens to be let's say 9 the value of
record Y at time 10 is C 11 maybe we're
从X到Y的转移类似，C 2选择时间戳为20，因为那是
doing a transfer from X to Y similarly C
2 chose timestamp of 20 because that was
提交时的实时时间，数据库将记住一组新的
the real time at commit time and the
database is gonna remember a new set of
记录这些旧记录，它会在20点说X也许我们做了一个
Records in addition these old ones it's
gonna say X at time 20 maybe we did a
在时间20从X到Y和Y的另一次转移等于12哦，所以现在我们有两个
another transfer from X to Y and Y at
time 20 equals 12 oh so now we have two
每个记录在不同时间的副本现在将出现事务3
copies of each record at different times
now transaction 3 is gonna come along
再一次，它大约在这个时候开始，并读取X，再一次，
and again it starts at about this time
and does a read of X and again it's
会很慢，所以你知道直到很长时间都不会读书
gonna be slow so you know it's not gonna
get around to reading wine till much
稍后实时得多，但是在事务3开始时
later much later in real time
however when transaction 3 started it
通过查看当前时间来选择时间戳记，所以让我们
chose a timestamp by looking at the
looking at the current time and so let's
说，因为我们实时知道交易3是在交易后开始的
say since we know in real time that
transaction 3 started after transaction
交易2之前的一个否，必须选择一项交易
one on before transaction 2
no it's got to have chosen a transaction
时间在10到20之间，让我们假设它从15开始
time somewhere between 10 and 20 and
let's suppose it started it time 15 and
自己选择了时间戳15，这意味着当它读取X时
chose timestamp 15 for itself so that
mean when it does the read of X it's
将发送一个请求，该请求包含X的本地副本将被陪伴
gonna send a request the local replica
that holds X and it's gonna accompany it
它的时间戳记是15它会说请给我最新的数据
with it it's time stamp of 15 it's gonna
say please give me the latest data as of
当然，事务2000的第15次执行了，但是
time 15 of course transaction 2000
executed yet and but nevertheless the
X的最高时间戳副本是从事务10写入的时间10开始的副本
highest time stamp copy of X is the one
from time 10 written by transaction 1 so
我们这次将获得9，通过事务2提交
we're gonna get 9 for this one time
passes transaction 2 commits now
事务3在公司再次进行第二次读取以适合读取请求
transaction 3 does the second read again
at a company suit the read requests with
它自己的时间戳记15将服务器居中现在服务器必须
its own time stamp of 15 Center the
server's now the server's have to
记录，但又一次因为服务器获取15的交易三分时间戳
records but again because the server
gets transaction threes time stamp of 15
它查看记录并说ha 15坐在这两个之间，我要返回
it looks at its records and say ha 15
sits between these two I'm gonna return
X的y的最高时间戳记录，它小于请求的时间
the highest time stamp record for X for
y it's less than the requested time
戳，这仍然是从时间10开始的Y版本，因此Y的读数将
stamp and that's still the version of Y
from time 10 so the read of Y will
返回11，本质上是X的读取
return at 11
that is the read of X essentially
发生在这个时候，但是因为我们想起了一个时间戳，
happens at this time but because we
remembered a time stamp and we have the
数据库保留数据的不同写入时间
database keep data as of different times
it was written
好像两次读取都发生在时间15而不是时间15的一次
it's as if both reads happened the time
15 instead of one at time 15 and one
稍后，现在您会看到，实际上这实际上是在模拟一个串行
later and now you'll see that in fact
this just essentially emulates a serial
一次执行，其中订单是时间戳订单事务1
one at a time execution in which the
order is timestamp order transaction 1
和交易-对不起，然后交易3然后是序列交易2
and transaction - sorry then transaction
3 then transaction 2 that is a serial
等同于实际产生的订单是时间戳
order that is equivalent to that was
also actually produced is the time stamp
10 15 20的订单
order of 10 15 20
好的，那是扳手真正作用的简化版本
alright okay so that's a simplified
version of what spanner does for really
交易，还有更多的复杂性，我将在稍后介绍
transactions there's more complexity
which I'll get to in a minute
您可能会遇到的一个问题是，为什么事务3可以读取一个
one question you might have is why it
was okay for transaction 3 to read an
y的旧值，它是在此时间点发出对Y的读取
old value of y that is it issued this
read of Y at this point in time the
为什么该值是12的最新数据，但实际得到的值是
freshest data for why was this value 12
but the value would actually got was
有意的是，陈旧的值不是最新的值，而是来自
intentionally a stale value not the
freshest value but the value from a
而之前这个值是11，那为什么还可以，为什么不使用
while ago this value 11 so why is that
okay why is it okay not to be using the
数据的最新版本以及相应的技术依据
freshest version of the data and the
kind of technical justification for that
是交易2和交易3是并发的，即
is that transaction 2 and transaction 3
are concurrent that is the overlap in
时间，这样交易2的时间范围就在这里和时间
time so those sort of time extent of
transaction 2 is here and the time
事务3的范围在这里是并发的，并且线性化的规则
extent of transaction 3 is here they're
concurrent and the rules for linearise
能力和外部一致性，或者如果两个事务并发，那么
ability and external consistency or that
if two transactions are concurrent then
允许数据库使用的串行命令可以放两个
the serial order that the database is
allowed to use can be can put the two
以任何顺序进行事务，并且数据库扳手选择在此处放置
transactions in either order and here
the database spanner has chosen to put
交易2在顺序2之前的交易3好的，罗伯特，我们有
transaction 3 before transaction 2 in
the serial order okay Robert we we have
一个学生问题是否总是像时间戳一样保持外部一致性
a student question does external
consistency like with timestamps always
表示很强的一致性，我是，是，我认为是
imply a strong consistency I'm
yes yes I think so
如果强一致性，强一致性通常是人们的意思是
if strong consistency strong consistency
usually what people mean by that is
我相信线性化能力和
linearise ability and I believe the
definition of linearise ability and
外部一致性是相同的，所以我会说是，另一个问题是
external consistency are the same so I
would say yes and another question how
这不是绝对会炸毁存储空间吗，这是一个很好的问题和答案
does this not absolutely blow up storage
that is a great question and the answer
肯定会炸毁存储空间，原因是现在的存储空间
is it definitely blows up storage and
the reason is that now the storage
系统必须保留多个副本数据记录，这些记录最近已被修改
system has to keep multiple copies data
records that have been recently modified
多次，这肯定是在成本和存储上都付出了代价
multiple times and that's definitely
expense both both this cost and storage
和内存中磁盘上的空间，也就像增加了一层
and space on the disk in the memory and
also it's just like an added layer of
您现在知道的簿记查找必须考虑时间戳和密钥
bookkeeping you know now lookups have to
consider the timestamps as well as keys
我认为存储费用并没有那么高，因为系统
the storage expense I think is not as
great as it could be because the system
丢弃旧记录，即纸张未说明政策是什么，但大概
discards old records that paper does not
say what the policy is but presumably
好吧，如果唯一的原因是一定要丢弃旧记录
well it must be discarding old records
certainly if the only reason for the
多个记录是实现这些类型的快照隔离
multiple records is to implement
snapshot isolation of these kinds of
交易，那么您真的不需要记住过去的价值
transactions then you don't really need
to remember values too far in the past
因为您只需要记住可以追溯到
because you only need to remember values
back to the sort of earliest time that a
交易本来可以开始的，现在仍在运行，如果您的
that a transaction could have started at
that's still running now and if your
大多数情况下，交易总是可以完成，或者通过杀死交易来强制完成，或者
transactions mostly you're always finish
or force the finish by killing them or
一分钟之内的事情，如果没有交易会花费超过一分钟的时间
something within say one minute if no
transaction can take longer than a
分钟，那么您只需要记住版本中的最后一分钟
minute then you only have to remember
the last minute of versions in the
实际上，该数据库现在暗示着它们
database now in fact the paper implies
that they
第二天比那晚，因为他们似乎有意支持
day two farther back than that because
it appears they support intentionally
支持这些快照读取，使它们能够支持看到您的想法
support these snapshot reads which allow
them to support the notion of seeing you
知道前一段时间的数据，您知道昨天或其他什么，但他们不知道
know data from a while ago you know
yesterday or something but they don't
说，但是垃圾收集策略是针对旧值的，所以我不知道
say but but the garbage collection
policy is for old values so I don't know
对他们来说会很昂贵，好吧，所以冰的理由
how expensive it would be for them okay
okay so the the justification for ice
合法的是，在外部一致性方面，唯一的规则是外部
legal is that in external consistency
that the only rule that external
一致性表明，如果一项交易已完成，则
consistency imposes is that if one
transaction has completed then a
在必须看到其权利之后开始的事务，因此t1可能已完成
transaction that starts after it must
see its rights so t1 may be t1 completed
假设t1在此时完成，而t3可能在之后才开始
let's say that t1 completed at this time
and t3 started just after it may be
外部一致性，但要求t3看到关键的权利，但由于c2
external consistency but demand that t3
sees key ones rights but since c2
绝对没有在t3开始之前完成，我们没有义务
definitely didn't finish before t3
started we have no obligation under
外部一致性43看教师权利
external consistency forty-three to see
teachers rights and indeed in this
例如，事实并非如此，这实际上是合法的，好吧，另一个问题来了
example it does not so it's actually
legal um okay another problem that comes
从某种意义上说，事务T 3需要读取数据
up is that the transaction T 3 is needs
to read data as of a particular
时间戳记，但您知道为什么这样做很理想，因为它允许
timestamp but you know the reason why
this is desirable is that were it allows
我们从同一数据中心的本地副本读取数据，但也许
us to read from the local replicas in
the same data center but maybe that
本地复制品是很少看到的paxos追随者
local replica is in the minority of
paxos followers that didn't see the
最新的日志记录了领导者，所以也许我们的本地副本可能永远都不会
latest log records the leader so maybe
our local replicas maybe it's never even
看到您知道从未见过对X＆Y的这些权利，但它仍然是一个版本
seen you know never saw these rights to
X&Y at all it's still back at a version
从松树上，你知道五六个或七个，所以如果我们不做一些聪明的事情
from pine you know five or six or seven
and so if we don't do something clever
当我们要求获得最高版本记录时，您所了解的不到
when we ask for the sort of highest
version record you know less than
时间戳15我们可能会得到一些实际上不是您的旧版本
timestamp 15 we may get some much older
version that's not actually the you
由交易一产生，需要查看
produced by transaction one which were
required to see
所以他的扳手处理这个问题的方式是我们的安全时间观念
so the way he spanner deals with this is
with our notion of safe time and the
独家新闻是每个副本都记得您知道它正在从其副本中获取日志记录
scoop is that each replica remembers you
know it's getting log records from its
税务负责人和日志记录表明，文件安排得如此
taxes leader and the log records it
turns out that the paper arranges so
领导发送日志记录并严格增加时间戳顺序
that the leader sends out log records
and strictly increasing timestamp order
因此副本可以查看从其领导者获得的最后一个日志记录
so a replica can look at the very last
log record it's gotten from its leader
知道它是如何更新的，如果我要求从时间戳15开始的值，但是
to know how up to dated it so if I ask
for a value as of timestamp 15 but the
副本仅从我的pax处获得日志条目是领导者几次邮票13
replica has only gotten log entries from
my pax was leader a few times stamp 13
副本会使我们延迟，直到得到日志，它才回答
the replicas gonna make us delay it's
not gonna answer until it's gotten a log
记录带领导者的时间戳记15，这可确保副本
record with time stamped 15 from the
leader and this ensures that replicas
在确定给定时间戳之前，不要回答请求
don't answer a request for a given
timestamp until they're guaranteed to
直到那个时间戳都知道领导者的一切，所以这可能
know everything from the leader up
through that time stamp so this may
延迟这可能会延迟读取
delay this may delay the reads okay
所以我一直假设的下一个问题是在本次讨论中
so the next question I've been assuming
I assumed in this discussion that the
时钟和所有不同的服务器完全同步，因此每个人的
clocks and all the different servers are
perfectly synchronized so everybody's
时钟说您完全知道1001和30秒，但是它变成
clock says you know 1001 and 30 seconds
at exactly the same time but it turns
导致您无法同步恰恰是您的时钟
out that you can't synchronize clocks
that precisely you it's basically
无法获得完全同步的时钟，原因是合理的
impossible to get perfectly synchronized
clocks and the reasons are reasonably
基本，所以主题是时间同步
fundamental so the topic is time
synchronization which is sort of making
确保时钟说出相同的实时值，不同的时钟读出相同的值
sure clocks say the same real time value
different clocks read the same value the
我会说基本的问题是时间定义为
I'll tell the sort of fundamental
problem is that time is defined as
基本上，它说的时间是关于一组高度准确的昂贵物品的
basically the time it says on a
collection of highly accurate expensive
在一组政府实验室中进行计时，因此我们无法直接阅读
clocks in a set of government
laboratories so we can't directly read
尽管我们知道这些政府实验室可以广播
them although we can know is that these
government laboratories can broadcast
时间以各种方式，广播需要时间，所以这是一些
the time in various ways and the
broadcast take time and so it's some
时间过后，可能是未知的时间过后，我们听到了有关
time later some possibly unknown time
later we hear these announcements of
您知道现在几点钟可能会在以下时间听到这些公告
what the time it's own you know it may
all hear these announcements at
由于延迟时间的不同，所以我实际上首先不想考虑
different times due to varying delays so
I actually first don't want to consider
如果没有时钟，如果对快照隔离有什么影响的问题
the problem of what the impact is if on
snapshot isolation if the clocks are not
同步他们不会的
synchronize which they won't be
好吧，如果时钟不存在怎么办？
okay so what if the clocks are
there's actually no problem at all for
扳手进行读写事务，因为使用了读写事务
the spanners readwrite transactions
because the readwrite transactions used
锁和两阶段提交，它们实际上并没有使用解决方案中的快照
locks and two-phase commit they're not
actually using snaps out of a solution
所以他们不在乎，因此读写事务仍将通过
so they don't care so the readwrite
transactions will still be serialized by
锁定两阶段锁定机制，所以我们只对发生的事情感兴趣
the lock the two-phase locking mechanism
so we're only interested in what happens
对于RF或只读事务，让我们假设一个只读事务
for an RF or read-only transaction so
let's suppose a read-only transaction
选择一个太大的时间戳，以至于在不久的将来
chooses a timestamp that is too large so
that is far in the future you know it's
现在是12:01 pm，并且它选择的时间戳记是下午1点C，因此如果
now 12:01 p.m. and it chooses a
timestamp at C 1 o'clock p.m. so if a
选择的时间戳记过大的事务实际上并不差劲
transactions chosen timestamps too big
that's actually not that bad what it'll
意思是它将执行读取请求，并将读取请求发送给某些
mean is that it will do read requests
it'll send a read request to some
副本会告诉您稍等片刻，您知道自己的时钟是
replicas the replicas would say wait a
minute you're you know your clock is
更进一步，您的提示音似乎比我上一个日志条目大得多
Farrer it's far greater your chime seems
far greater than the last log entry I
看到我的pax是领导者，所以我要让你等到PAX在
saw for my pax was leader so I'm gonna
make you wait until the PAX was at the
时间和日志条目，Paxos领导者赶上了您的时间
time and the log entries and the Paxos
leader catches up to the time you've
要求我只回答，所以这是正确的，但读者会很慢
requested I'm only gonna respond then so
this is correct but slow the reader will
被迫离开世界上不是最坏的情况，但是如果我们有
be forced away that's not the worst
in the world but what happens if we have
一个只读事务，它的时间戳太小，这将
a read-only transaction and it's
timestamp is too small and this would
对应于它的时钟少或设置错误，所以说
correspond to its clock being less
either set wrong so that it's said in
过去或者也许它最初设置正确，但是时钟的时钟在滴答作响
the past or maybe it was originally set
correctly but the clock its clock ticks
太慢了，这是一个明显引起正确性问题的问题
too slowly the problem with this this is
a obviously causes a correctness problem
这将导致违反外部一致性，因为多版本
this will cause a violation of external
consistency because the multi version
数据库，您会给它一个过去一个小时之前的时间戳
databases you'll give it a timestamp
that's far in the past say an hour ago
并且数据库将从中读取与之关联的时间戳记
and the database will read you a value
associated with it the timestamp from an
一小时前，可能会忽略最近的写入，因此使用分配时间戳记
hour ago which may ignore more recent
writes so using a assigning a timestamp
交易太小会导致您错过最近提交的交易
to a transaction that's too small will
cause you to miss recent committed
写，这是对外部一致性的侵犯，所以不是外部
writes and that's a violation of
external consistency so not externally
所以在这里我们实际上有一个问题，即时钟是
so so we actually have a problem here
the assumption that the clocks were
同步实际上是一个非常认真的假设，并且您不能
synchronized is in fact a very serious
assumption and the fact that you cannot
依靠它意味着除非我们做某事，否则系统将是
count on it means that unless we do
something the system is going to be
好的，这样我们可以完全同步时钟了吗
incorrect all right so so can we
synchronize clocks perfectly all right
那将是理想的事情，如果不是，那么为什么呢？
that would be the ideal thing and if not
why not so so what about clock
同步，正如我提到的那样，它实际上是
synchronization the as I mentioned we're
done come from this it's actually a
收集时钟和政府实验室的中位数
collection of the kind of median of a
collection of clocks and government labs
我们听到的时间是通过各种协议广播的
the way that we hear about the time is
that it's broadcast by various protocols
有时通过无线电协议，例如GPS基本上为扳手做什么
sometimes by radio protocols like
basically what GPS is doing for spanner
是GPS充当广播当前时间的无线电广播系统
is a GPS acts as a radio broadcast
system that broadcasts the current time
从一些政府实验室通过GPS卫星到坐在
from some government lab through the GPS
satellites to GPS receiver sitting in
Google机房，还有许多其他无线电协议，例如WWB
the Google machine rooms and there's a
number of other radio protocols like WWB
是另一个用于广播当前时间的较旧的无线电协议，
is another older radio protocol for
broadcasting the current time and
有更新的协议，例如可以在
there's newer protocols like there's
this NTP protocol that operates over the
所以基本上也负责广播时间的互联网
Internet that also is in charge of
basically broadcasting time so the sort
系统图的一部分是，有一些政府实验室和政府实验室
of system diagram is that there are some
government labs and the government labs
精确的时钟定义了一种普遍的时间概念，即
with their accurate clocks define a
universal notion of time that's called
UTC，所以我们有一些实验室的UTC来自某些时钟，那么我们就知道一些
UTC so we've UTC coming from some clocks
in some labs then we have some you know
无线电互联网广播或扳手的情况下，我们可以
radio internet broadcast or something
for the case of spanner it's the we can
想到政府允许向GPS卫星广播
think of the government allowed to
broadcasting to GPS satellites the
卫星依次广播，而广播公司您知道数百万个GPS
satellites in turn broadcast and the
broadcaster you know the millions of GPS
那里的接收器，您可以购买一对夫妇的GPS接收器
receivers that are out there
you can buy GPS receivers for a couple
一百美元，它将解码GPS信号中的时间戳，
hundred bucks that will decode the
timestamps in the in the GPS signals and
可以让您随时了解校正时间的最新信息
sort of keep you up to date with exactly
what the time is corrected for the
政府实验室与GPS卫星之间的传播延迟，以及
propagation delay between the government
labs and the GPS satellites and also
校正了您当前位置的GPS卫星之间的延迟，并且
corrected for the delay between the GPS
satellites in your current position and
然后每个数据中心都有一个GPS接收器，该接收器连接到
then there's in each data center there's
a GPS receiver that's connected up to
本文所说的时间主控器是一台服务器，将会有更多
what the paper calls a time master which
is some server there's going to be more
而不是数据中心中的一种，以防万一发生故障，然后
than one of these for data center in
case one fails and then there's all the
数据中心中数百个正在运行扳手的服务器
hundreds of servers in the data center
that are running spanner either as
服务器或作为客户端的每个服务器都将定期发送请求
servers or as clients each one of them
is going to periodically send a request
说到当地时间几点了，通常不止一件
saying aw what time is it to the local
one or more usually more than one piece
感觉到时间大师，时间大师会回复哦
one feels to the time masters and the
time master will reply with oh you know
我认为GPS的当前接收时间已经内置了
I think the current time has received
for GPS is such-and-such now built into
不幸的是，这是一定程度的不确定性和主要来源
this unfortunately is a certain amount
of uncertainty and the primary sources
我认为不确定性存在根本性的不确定性
of uncertainty I think well there's
there's fundamentally uncertainty in
我们实际上并不知道我们离GPS卫星有多远
that we don't actually know how far we
are from the GPS satellites exactly so
您知道即使GPS，无线电信号也要花费一些时间
the you know radio signals take some
amount of time even though the GPS
卫星确切知道现在是几点，这些信号需要一些时间才能到达
satellite knew exactly what time it is
those signals take some time to get to
我们的GPS接收器我们不确定这是什么意思
our GPS receiver we're not sure what
that is that means that when the Jeep we
从GPS卫星的无线电消息中获取一条消息，说正好12
get a message from the radio message
from the GPS satellite saying exactly 12
你知道传播延迟是否可能
o'clock
you know if the propagation delay might
一直以来，您都知道几纳秒的时间，这意味着
have been you know a couple of
nanoseconds that mean that's there were
实际上，传播延迟比实际不确定性要大得多
actually the propagation delays much
more than that it's really uncertainty
传播延迟意味着我们并不确定
in the propagation delay means that
we're not really sure exactly whether
总是12点钟或一点点之后
it's 12 o'clock or a little before a
little after in addition all the times
在沟通时，您不确定是否需要考虑
at time is communicated there's
did uncertainty that you have to account
的最大来源是，当服务器在
for and the biggest sources are that
when a server sends requests after a
如果响应说是恰好是12点，那么它会得到响应，但是
while it gets a response if the response
says it's exactly 12 o'clock but the
数量，但是说第二遍，您知道服务器发送请求之间的间隔
amount but um say a second pass you know
between when the server sent the request
当我得到响应时，所有服务器都知道即使主服务器
and when I got the response all the
server knows is that even if the master
服务器知道的正确时间是该时间在
had the correct time all the server
knows is that the time is within a
12点的第二点，因为也许这可能是即时请求，但是
second of 12 o'clock because maybe that
may be the request was instant but the
回复被延迟，或者请求被延迟了一秒钟，响应
reply was delayed or maybe the request
was delayed by a second and the response
那是事件，所以您真正知道的是它在您知道的12点之间
was the incident so all you really know
is that it's between you know 12 o'clock
零秒十二点和一秒钟还可以，所以总有这样
and zero seconds and twelve o'clock and
one second okay so there's always this
不确定性以及我们真正不能忽略的原因，因为
uncertainty and in order to which we
really can't ignore though because the
我们在这里谈论毫秒的不确定性，我们会发现
uncertainties we're talking about
milliseconds here and we're gonna find
这些不确定性和时间直接关系到这些如何
out that these that the uncertainty and
the time goes directly to the these how
这些安全的等待时间必须是多长，其他一些停顿时间必须是多长时间
long these safe waits have to be and how
long some other pauses have to be the
提交等待，我们将看到，因此您知道毫秒级别的不确定性
commit wait as we'll see so you know
uncertainty in the level of milliseconds
是一个严重的问题，另一个很大的不确定性是
is a serious problem the other big
uncertainty is that each of these
服务器每隔一段时间仅向主服务器请求当前时间
servers only request the current time
from the master every once in a while
说每分钟或每隔一分钟，在每台服务器之间运行
say every minute or however often and
between that the each server runs its
自己的本地时钟，使时间从上次的最后一个时间开始
own local clock that sort of keeps the
time starting with the last time from
师父，那些本地时钟实际上是非常糟糕的，并且可能会漂移
the master those local clocks are
actually pretty bad and can drift by
服务器与主服务器对话的时间之间的毫秒数
things by milliseconds between times
that the server talks to the master and
因此系统必须添加未知但估计的局部漂移
so the system has to sort of add the
unknown but estimated drift of the local
把握时间的不确定性，所以我要捕捉这种不确定性
clock to the uncertainty of the time so
I'm in order to capture this uncertainty
并解决它
and account for it
扳手使用这种实时计划，在这种情况下，当您问几点到几点
spanner uses this true time scheme in
which when you ask what time it is what
您实际上是作为这些TT间隔事件之一返回的，
you actually get back as one of these TT
interval things which is a pair of an
最早的时间和最近的最早的时​​间是他们的时间越早越早
earliest time and a latest earliest time
is their early early as the time could
可能是第二个是最近的时间，当
possibly be and the second is the latest
the time can possibly be so when the
您知道的应用程序会进行此库调用，并要求获取时间
application you know makes this library
call that asked for the time it gets
返回该付款人，它所知道的是当前时间介于
back this payer all it knows is that the
current time is somewhere between
在这种情况下，最早和最新的信息可能就是最早的
earliest and latest that's what you know
earliest might be in this case earliest
可能是十二点钟，可能是一秒钟十二点钟
might be twelve o'clock and may this
might be twelve o'clock in one second
只是我们保证正确的时间不少于
just just our guarantee that the that
the correct time isn't less than
最早，并且不比最新大，我们不知道之间
earliest and isn't greater than latest
what we don't know where between
否则还可以，所以这就是交易时
otherwise okay
so this is what uh when a transaction
问系统现在是什么时间，这就是实际的交易
asks the system what time it is this is
this is what the transaction actually
从时间系统回到现在
gets back from the time system and now
让我们回到最初的问题是，如果时钟太慢，
let's return to our original problem was
that if the clock was too slow that a
只读事务可能会读取过去的数据太远而不会
read-only transaction might read data
too far in the past and that it wouldn't
从最近提交的事务中读取数据，所以我们需要知道什么
read data from a recent committed
transaction so we need to know what
我们正在寻找的是扳手如何在其真实概念中使用这些TT间隔
we're looking for is how spanner uses
these TT intervals in its notion of true
时间，以确保尽管不确定什么时间
time in order to ensure that despite
uncertainty in what time it is
事务外部一致性是只读事务，它是
transaction a external consistency that
is a read-only transaction it's
保证看到由交易利率交易完成的写操作
guaranteed to see writes done by a
transaction rate transaction that
在我们面前已经完成，并且论文谈到了两个规则
completed before us and there are two
rules that the paper talks about that
合谋执行此规则以及第4-1节中的两条规则-其中一项
conspire to enforce this and the two
rules which are in section 4-1 - one of
这是开始规则
them is the start rule
另一个是提交等待
and the other is commit wait
此注释规则告诉我们实际上是什么时间戳训练什么时间戳
this note rule tells us what time stamps
trains actually what time stamps
交易选择，基本上说交易时间戳必须是
transactions choose and basically says
that a transactions timestamp has to be
等于当前时间的最新时间的一半，所以现在是TT
equal to the latest half of the true
time current time so this is T T now
调用返回最早的最新对之一，即当前时间和
call which returns one of those earliest
latest pairs that's the current time and
交易时间戳必须是最新的，这将是
that transactions timestamp has to be
the latest that is it's going to be a
保证还没有发生的时间，因为真正的时间是
time that's guaranteed not to have
happened yet because the true time is
在最早和最新之间，对于只读事务，这是一个标志
between earliest and latest and for a
read-only transaction it's a sign the
截至其开始并进行读或写事务的最晚时间为
latest time as of its the time it starts
and for a read or write transaction is
在开始提交时为其分配一个最新的时间戳
to assign a timestamp this latest value
as of the time it starts to commit
好的，所以开始规则说这是扳手选择提交时间戳的方式
okay so the start rule says this is how
spanner chooses time stamps the commit
仅适用于读写事务的权重规则表示，当
weight rule only for readwrite
transactions says that when a
交易协调员，您知道收集票并看到
transaction coordinator is you know
collects the votes and sees that it's
能够提交并在选择此时间戳后选择时间戳
able to commit and and chooses a time
stamp after it chooses this time stamp
它需要延迟等待一定的时间，直到我不得不
it's required to delay to wait a certain
amount of time before til I have to
实际提交并写入值并释放锁，以便进行读写事务
actually commit and write the values and
release locks so a readwrite transaction
必须延迟到开始思考时选择的时间戳记
has to delay until it's time stamps that
it chose when it was starting to think
关于提交的时间最早小于当前时间
about commit is less than the current
time the earliest
抱歉，这是怎么回事
sorry
so what's going on here is the
现在坐在调用TS的循环中，并且一直停留到该循环中，直到时间戳记
sits in a loop calling TS now and it
stays in that loop until the timestamp
它在提交过程开始时选择的值小于
that it had chosen at the beginning of
the commit process is less than the
当前时间最早的一半，这保证了从现在开始
current times earliest half and what
this guarantees is that since now the
最早的正确时间大于交易时间戳
earliest possible correct time is
greater than the transactions timestamp
这意味着当提交等待为
that means that when this loop is
finished when the commit wait is
绝对保证交易完成此时间戳
过去可以，那么系统实际上如何利用这两个
be in the past okay so how does the
system actually make use of these two
规则以对只读事务强制实施外部一致性
rules in order to enforce external
consistency for read-only transactions I
想回到我们这里，或者我想在
want to go back to our or I want to cook
up a someone simplified scenario in
为了说明这一点，我将想象写作交易
order to illustrate this so I'm gonna
imagine that the writing transactions
每次只写一次只是降低复杂性，我们说有两个
only do one write each just reduce the
complexity let's say that there's two
读/写事务，所以我们有t0和t1是读/写事务，
read/write transactions so we have t0
and t1 are read/write transactions and
他们都写X，我们有一个t2来读X，我们想
they both write X and we have a t2 which
is going to read X and we want to make
确保t2看到您知道它将在时间戳上使用快照隔离
想确保看到最新的书面价值，所以我们要想象
want to make sure that sees the latest
written value so we're going to imagine
t2写X并向X写一个，然后提交我们将要执行的操作
that t2 does a write of X and writes one
to X and then commits we're going to
想象一下，对不起，t1做爱，也来t2
imagine that
sorry t1 write sex and come at t2 also
写X向X写一个值2，我们需要区分可以准备
writes X writes a value 2 to X and we
need to distinguish between can prepare
并提交，所以我们要说这真的是交易的准备
and commit so we're going to say it it's
really a prepare that the transaction
选择其时间戳，因此这是选择时间戳的点，
chooses its timestamps so this is a
point at which it chooses timestamp and
它在一段时间后提交，然后我们假设t2
it commits some time later and then
we're imagining by assumption that t2
在t1完成后开始，因此它将读取X
starts after t1 finishes so it's going
to read X
之后，我们要确保它可以看到-好的，让我们假设
afterwards and we want to make sure it
sees - all right so let's suppose that
t0选择一个提交的时间戳记写数据库，假设t1开始
t0 chooses a time stamp of one commits
writes the database let's say t1 starts
在选择时间戳时，它会得到一些它不会得到一个
at the time it chooses a time stamp it's
gonna get some it's not get a single
真实时间系统中的数字确实得到了一系列您知道的数字
number from the true time system really
gets a range of numbers you know
最早和最新的价值，比如说在选择时间戳记时
earliest and a latest value let's say at
the time it chooses its time stamp it
最早获得的值的范围是1，而
the range of values that earliest time
it gets is 1 and the latest field in the
当前时间是10，所以规则说它必须选择10作为最新值
current time is 10 so the rule says that
it must choose 10 the latest value as
它的时间戳记，因此t1将与时间步10一起提交
its time stamp so t1 is gonna commit
with its time step 10
现在您还不能提交，因为提交权重规则表示必须等待
now you can't commit yet because the
commit weight rule says it has to wait
直到确定时间戳是过去的时间，这样事务1才能进行
until it's time stamp is guaranteed to
be in the past so transaction 1 is going
坐在那里继续问现在几点了
to sit there keep asking what time is it
what time is it
直到它返回的间隔不包括时间10，所以在某个时候
until it gets an interval back that
doesn't include time 10 so at some point
会问现在几点了，我们会最早
it's gonna ask what time it is is gonna
get a time that we're the earliest
价值观是11，精英是我不知道，比如说20，现在我要说AHA
values 11 and elitist is I don't know
let's say 20 and now I was gonna say AHA
现在我知道我的时间Sam一定会过去，我可以
now I know that my time Sam it's
guaranteed to be in the past and I can
提交，所以t1实际上是它的提交等待时间，坐在那里等待
commit so t1 will actually this is its
commit wait period to sit there and wait
提交事务之前需要一段时间，现在提交事务之后会出现两次
for a while before it commits okay now
after it commits transaction two comes
沿着怪物B Dex会选择一个时间戳，我们也假设它是
along a monster B Dex it's gonna choose
a time stamp also we're assuming that it
在t1完成后开始，因为这是外部的有趣场景
starts after t1 finishes because that's
the interesting scenario for external
一致性，所以让我们说它何时要求时间
consistency so let's say when it asks
for the time it asks at a time after
时间11，所以它将返回一个包含时间11的间隔
time 11 so it's going to get back an
interval that includes time 11
因此，让我们假设它从十点开始又恢复了一点
so let's suppose it gets back in a
little bit goes from time ten this is
最早的时间是十二点，最晚的时间是十二点
the earliest and time twelve the latest
and of course the time twelve has to be
因为我们知道交易第二个开始之后至少必须是11点
since we know that must be at least time
11 since transaction two started after
交易一完成，这意味着第11个必须小于最新的
transaction one finished that means that
the 11th must be less than the latest
价值交易2将选择最新的1/2作为其时间戳，因此
value transaction 2 is going to choose
this latest 1/2 as its timestamp so it's
会实际选择时间戳记12，在本示例中，当它进行读取时
gonna actually choose timestamp 12 and
in this example when it does its read
它要问存储系统哦，我想从时间戳12开始阅读
it's gonna ask the storage system oh I
want to read as of timestamp 12 since
事务1以时间戳10编写，这意味着您知道
transaction 1 wrote with timestamp 10
that means that you know assuming the
安全等待安全时间机制工作，我们实际上会读正确的
safe wait the safe time machinery works
we're actually gonna read the correct
价值，这里发生的是
value and what's going on here is that
所以这碰巧解决了，但确实可以保证
the so this happened to work out but
indeed it's guaranteed to work out if
只要事务1提交后事务2开始，事务2
transaction 2 as long as transaction 2
starts after transaction 1 commits and
原因是提交权重导致事务1无法完成提交
the reason is that commit weight causes
transaction 1 not to finish committing
直到确定其时间戳记已过去
until its timestamp is guaranteed to be
in the past
好的，因此事务1选择时间戳，可以保证提交
all right so transaction 1 chooses a
timestamp it's guaranteed to commit
在该时间戳记事务2之后，在提交它之后开始，所以我们
after that timestamp transaction 2
starts after the commit it and so we
对其最早的价值一无所知，但最新
don't know anything about what its
earliest value will be but its latest
值肯定会在当前时间之后，但是我们知道
value is guaranteed to be after the
current time but we know that the
当前时间是在T 1的提交时间之后，因此可以传授最新信息
current time is after the commit time of
T 1 and therefore that teaches latest
值选择的时间戳保证在C提交之后
value the timestamp it chooses is
guaranteed to be after when C committed
因此，在C使用的时间戳之后，因为事务2如果
and therefore after the timestamp that C
used and because transaction 2 if
事务2在T 1完成后开始
transaction 2 starts after T 1 finishes
transaction 2 is guaranteed to get a
较高的时间戳和快照隔离机制
higher timestamp
and the snapshot isolation machinery the
多个版本将导致其读取到所有较低的值
multiple versions will cause it to read
to it's read to see all lower valued
从所有较低时戳的事务中写入信息，这意味着教您
writes from all the lower time-stamped
transactions that means teach you is
将会看到t1 nom，这基本上意味着我们就是这个
going to see t1 nom and that basically
means that we're this this is how
扳手为其交易强制执行外部一致性，因此任何问题
spanner enforces external consistency
for its transactions so any questions
关于这个机械，嗯，我要退后一点
about this machinery alright um I'm
gonna step back a little bit there's
从我的角度来看，实际上发生了两件事：快照
really from my point of view sort of two
big things going on here one is snapshot
本身的隔离快照本身的隔离足以为您提供
isolation by itself snapshot isolation
by itself is enough to give you that
它保留了多个版本，并为每个交易提供了时间戳
it's keeping the multiple versions and
giving every transaction a timestamp
快照隔离保证为您提供可序列化的只读事务
snapshot isolation is guaranteed to give
you serializable read-only transactions
因为基本上快照隔离意味着我们要
because basically what snapshot
isolation means is that we're going to
使用这些时间戳作为等效的串行顺序以及诸如保险柜之类的东西
use these timestamps as the equivalent
serial order and things like the safe
等待安全时间，以确保只读事务在读取时确实能够读取
wait the safe time ensure that read-only
transactions really do read as of their
时间戳可以看到之前的每个读写事务，而之后没有
time stamps see every readwrite
transaction before that and none after
因此，快照隔离实际上有两部分
that so there's really two pieces
snapshot isolation snapshot isolation by
尽管实际上它本身不仅经常被扳手使用，而且通常不被
itself though is actually often used not
just by spanner but generally doesn't by
一个自我保证的外部一致性，因为在分布式系统中
a self guarantee external consistency
because in a distributed system it's
不同的计算机选择时间戳，因此我们不确定是否存在
different computers choosing the
timestamp so we're not sure there's
时间戳将遵守外部一致性，即使它们会交付
timestamps will obey external
consistency even if they'll deliver
序列化功能，因此除了快照隔离扳手外，还具有
serialize ability so in addition to
snapshot isolation spanner also has
同步时间戳，它是同步时间戳加上提交
synchronized timestamps and it's the
synchronized timestamps plus the commit
重量规则，允许扳手也保证外部一致性
weight rule that allow spanner to
guarantee external consistency as well
作为可序列化性，而再次使所有这些有趣的原因是
as serializability and again the reason
why all this is interesting is that
程序员非常喜欢事务，而且我非常喜欢外部一致性
programmers really like transactions and
I really like external consistency
因为这使应用程序更容易编写
because that makes the applications much
easier to write
传统上不会在分布式设置中提供它们，因为它们也是如此
they traditionally not been provided in
distributed settings because they're too
速度慢，所以扳手设法释放的事实使它成为只读的
slow and so the fact that spanner
manages to release make read-only
交易非常快，非常有吸引力，没有锁定，没有两阶段
transactions very fast is extremely
attractive right no locking no two-phase
提交，甚至没有远距离读取它们的只读事务
commit and not even any distant reads
for a read-only transactions they
从本地副本非常有效地运行，这又是一件好事
operate very efficiently from the local
replicas and again this is what's good
基本上改善了10个延迟，
for a basically attend factor of 10
latency improvement as measured in
表3和表6，但只是提醒您，这还不是全部，还不是全部
tables 3 & 6 but just to remind you it's
not all it's not all fabulous the the
所有这台出色的机器，实际上仅适用于只读事务
all this wonderful machine it really
only applies to read-only transactions
读写事务仍然使用两阶段提交和锁定，并且有一个
readwrite transactions still use
two-phase commit and locks and there's a
出于安全考虑，甚至连扳手也会出现阻塞的情况的数量
number of cases in which even spanner
will have the block like due to the safe
时间和提交等待，但只要它们的时间足够准确
time and the commit wait but as long as
their times are accurate enough
这些提交权重可能相对较小，可以概括一下
these commit weights are likely to be
relatively small okay just to summarize
当时的扳手有点突破，因为
the spanner at the time was kind of a
breakthrough because it was very rare to
查看运行分布式事务的已部署系统，其中数据
see deployed systems that operate
distributed transactions where the data
在地理位置上完全不同的数据中心中，我很惊讶您知道
was geographically in very different
data centers I'm surprising you know
扳手的人惊讶于有人正在使用一个数据库
spanner people were surprised that
somebody was using a database that
实际上做得很好，而且性能是可以忍受的，
actually did a good job of this and that
the performance was tolerable and the
快照隔离和时间戳可能是最可能的一部分
snapshot isolation and a timestamp being
part of the probably the most
本文有趣的方面，而这就是我今天要说的
interesting aspects of the paper and
that is all I have to say for today any
最后一个问题好吧，我想
last questions okay
I think on
我们要去看农场，这是一个截然不同的地方
we're gonna we're going to see farm
which is a sort of very different slice
通过提供高性能交易的愿望，所以我见
through the desire to provide very high
performance transactions so I'll see you
星期四
on Thursday